Dominic Toretto.
判多米尼克·特若圖
You are hereby sentenced to serve 25 years to life
二十五年有期徒刑
at the Lompoc Maximum Security Prison system
收押於隆波克最高警備監獄
without the possibility of early parole.
不得提前假釋
This is all the aftermath of a daring, daylight breakout.
隆波克囚車車禍現場連線--
in the search for Dominic Toretto
搜尋多米尼克·特若圖
and his accomplices Brian O'Conner and Mia Toretto.
和其同夥布萊恩·歐康納及米亞·特若圖
But despite every eye in the country looking for them
儘管舉國之力都在盡力搜捕
where Toretto and O'Conner are now is anyone's guess.
特若圖和歐康納仍下落不明
It's got to be it, right?
是這堥S錯吧
Let's get out of here.
我們離開這
Easy, friends.
別緊張  夥計們
She's with me.
她是自己人
Mia.
米亞
Vince.
文森
Buster.
臭小子
Come on.
來吧
Dom here yet?
多姆來了嗎
No.
沒
When was the last time you heard from him?
上次有他消息是什麼時候
A couple of weeks ago. Up in Ecuador somewhere.
幾星期前  像是在厄瓜多爾
- How does it feel? - What's that?
-感覺怎麼樣  -什麼怎麼樣
To be on the other side of a wanted poster?
捕人變成被捕
He'll show up.
他會現身的
Dom's?
多姆的?
Time for bed little one.
小傢伙該睡覺了
Can I bring him?
我能帶他去嗎
Of course.
當然
Good night.
晚安
Excuse me, sorry.
不好意思
Why Rio, Vince?
為什麼來堿  文森
You mean after you screwed everything up in LA?
你是說在你把洛杉磯搞得一團糟以後嗎
Ended up free-falling through South America, you know,
無奈落腳在南美
hitting every hellhole on the way down.
一路躲躲藏藏
Would have kept on going if not for Rosa.
要不是為羅莎  還得繼續逃
Does he know?
他知道嗎
So, listen.
聽著
There is a job coming up.
現在有個活兒
I was hoping Dom was going to be here by now
我希望多姆也能在這  但是
but this one is clean enough we can do it without him.
這次很簡單  沒他也能做
It's a good gig. Couple of high-end cars, easy targets.
大買賣  幾輛高端車  目標簡單
Guy I know is putting together a team to swipe them.
一個熟人招了些夥計打算幹這票
Just need a few more willing bodies.
就是還缺幾個人手
I don't know.
我不知道
Look, the way the car scene is down here
那批車路過這
we can unload them quick and get top dollar.
我們只需快速把它們裝卸就能拿大錢
It's easy money.
這錢賺的容易
And from where I'm sitting,
就我看來
it looks like you both could use the payday.
你倆都可以撈上一筆
What are you reading?
你在看什麼
Travel guide.
旅遊指南
Yeah?
是嗎
Tokyo.
東京
Moscow.
莫斯科
Goa.
果阿邦
You want to know what all of these places have in common?
這些地方都什麼相同點
Huh?
什麼
No extradition.
不能引渡
Here we go.
走啦
Excuse me, buddy.
借過  夥計
Okay.
好了
Hey, we've found them.
找到了
Yeah, second-to-the-last freighter.
從後面數第二間
What is it?
這是什麼
DEA tags. These cars have been seized.
藥品管理局標籤  這車被查封了
Look who showed up.
看  誰來了
God, I'm so happy you're okay.
天啊  真高興你沒事
I thought I told you to lay low.
我告訴你們要低調行事
Been running on fumes. Had to make a call.
我彈盡糧絕了  不得不做
Hey! Quit talking. We only got the two-minute window.
別扯淡了  我們只有兩分鐘
Let's go, Vince.
走  文森
I'm taking the GT40.
我要那輛GT40[福特一跑車型號]
Ladies first.
女士優先
This car suits me better.
這車更適合我
See you, baby.
待會見  寶貝
It's okay... we're all going to the same place.
沒關係  我們都去一個地方
We'll get the car there.
到那兒再把車弄回來
Change of plans. Wait for my call.
計劃有變  等我電話
Let's go!
放下去
Where is she going?
她去哪
Where is she going? Hey!
她要去哪
We're being robbed! Whatever happens, don't stop the train!
我們被劫了  無論如何別讓火車停下來
Go after the girl!
快追那女的
Hurry up!
快
Access card! Get the access card!
門禁卡  快拿門禁卡
Shit.
該死
Bridge! There is a bridge!
多姆  那有個橋
Luggage car is clear.
行李車廂沒人
Freeze!
不許動
Oh, Shit!
該死
You had to make a call, huh?
不得不幹一票  啊
Shitty call, O'Conner.
什麼爛活兒  歐康納
Shitty call.
爛活兒
You two stirred up quite a bit of trouble today.
你們今天可惹了不少麻煩
Three of my men dead.
我的人死了三個
Three DEA agents along with them.
三個藥品管理局的人也掛了
Of course,
當然
this is business and sometimes things go astray.
做生意有得有失
All I care about is the car.
我只關心車
Tell me where it is, and I'll let you go.
告訴我在哪  就放你們走
This roofing plastic says you're full of shit.
純屬扯淡
I don't know how you guys do business in your part of the world,
我不知道在你們那堿O怎麼做生意的
but here in Rio,
但在堿
I like it when all parties know what they're up against.
所有人都清楚他們的對手是誰
That's funny.
好笑
Because it goes both ways.
井水不犯河水
You know,
那個
I hear your sister is very beautiful.
我聽說你妹妹很漂亮
Wherever she hides
就算她藏到天涯海角
I Will find her.
我也能找到她
The American fugitives killed
美國逃犯在火車搶劫中
three DEA agents during a train robbery...
殺了三名藥管局官員
...Police warn they are armed and extremely dangerous.
警方警告市民逃犯帶有槍支並極其危險
Anyone with information should contact law enforcement immediately...
任何人有嫌犯任何消息  請及時與警方聯繫
Mia?
米亞
You okay?
你還好嗎
Yeah, you all right?
還行  你呢
Just like a Toretto.
不愧是特若圖家的
Where's Vince?
文森呢
That's a good question.
問得好
He'll be here.
他會來的
Guys, we're all over the news.
新聞堻ㄛO我們的消息
They're blaming us for the
他們把三個藥管局官員的死
killing of those DEA agents on the train.
怪到我們頭上
Which means we just jumped to the top of the wanted list.
我們又成了頭號通緝犯
The feds have got to show everyone their agents are off limits
聯邦探子哪兒都是
and they're going to send their best guys.
他們會派最厲害的人馬
We got to get out of here.
我們得離開這
One thing we know for sure
有件事可以肯定
is that they wanted this car.
他們想要這車
Because something is in it.
車埵陸
If we find out what it is, we'll know what we're up against.
我們查清楚  就知道對手是誰了
All right, listen up!
聽著
The men we're after are professional runners.
我們追捕的是專業車手
They like speed and are guaranteed to go down the hardest possible way
他們喜歡速度  而且敢鋌而走險
so make sure you got your funderwear on.
所有要保證彈藥充足
We find them, we take them as a team, and we bring them back.
找到後一個不落全部帶來回
And above all else, we don't ever, ever let them get into cars.
最重要一點  絕不能讓他們弄到車
Crime scene is 10 hours old and counting, men. Let's go hunting.
據事發近10小時了  開始行動
Agente Hobbs! Chief of Police, Jono Alemeida.
霍布斯警官  我是警察局長  齊諾·阿米達
Luke.
盧克
Sorry to hear about the loss of your men.
你手下的殉職  我很遺憾
Is all this really necessary to apprehend two men?
就兩個人值得這麼大動干戈嗎
Let me tell you something about these two men.
這兩個人來頭不小
One is a former federal officer,
一個是前聯邦警官
been in deep cover for five years.
做了五年臥底
He knows every way you're going to come for him.
對我們的行動瞭如指掌
The other one is a professional criminal, escaped prison twice,
另一個是職業罪犯  兩次越獄
spent half his life on the run avoiding folks like you.
大半生都在躲像你我這樣的人
Well, if there's anything we can do to help the DSS...
如果有什麼可以幫忙
Two things. One, I need a translator.
兩件事  一  我需要個翻譯
We have plenty in the public relations department.
我們公關部有很多...
Elena Neves.
埃莉娜·奈維思
- A patrol officer? - You heard me.
-是個巡警嗎  -沒錯
But why? We have many more experienced people.
為什麼  其他人更有經驗
I like her smile.
我喜歡她的笑
What's the second thing?
第二件是什麼
Stay the fuck out of my way.
別他媽擋我的道
Brian. Hm?
布萊恩
I have something I have to tell you.
我有事要告訴你
God damn.
靠
What a mess!
真夠亂的
Where you been, man?
你去哪了
You better check that tone.
你怎麼說話呢
And you just better answer the goddamn question.
你最好快回答我
Stop it! Both of you.
住手  你們兩個
Where were you, Vince?
你去哪了  文森
Guys all over the favelas asking about you.
貧民窟的混混都在打聽你
Couldn't get out of there without leading them straight to you.
非要弄清你的下落才讓我脫身
Had to wait them out.
弄完了才來
That is such horseshit
放狗屁
That was your job, and those were your guys! Hey!
這次你攬的活兒  我們是為你賣命
Hey! Enough, O'Conner!
夠了  歐康納
If he said he didn't do it, he didn't do it.
他說沒做就沒做
Go walk it off.
一邊兒待著去
Look, I would love to expand my operations into your countries
我願意在貴國擴大我公司的業務
but, quite frankly, your business methods are too violent.
但老實說  你行事風格太過暴力
Let me tell you a true story.
我給你講個故事
Five hundred years ago, the Portuguese and the Spanish came here,
五百年前  西葡兩國殖民者來到這
each trying to get the country from their natives.
都想把這埵洶J囊中
The Spaniards arrived, guns blazing,
西班牙人帶著長槍短
determined to prove who was boss.
誓要證明誰是老大
The natives killed every single Spaniard.
但全被土著人殺了
Personally, I prefer the methods of the Portuguese.
我個人更欣賞葡萄牙人的方法
They came bearing gifts.
他們奉上禮物
Mirrors, scissors, trinkets.
鏡子  剪刀  毛毯
Things that the natives couldn't get on their own,
一些土著人自己沒有的東西
but to continue receiving them,
想用這些東西
they had to work for the Portuguese.
就得聽命於葡萄牙人
And that's why all Brazilians speak Portuguese today.
所以現在巴西人都說葡萄牙語
Now, if you dominate the people with violence,
如果你想以暴制人
they will eventually fight
最終他們會反抗
back because they have nothing to lose.
因為他們沒什麼輸不起的
And that's the key.
這是關鍵
I go into the favelas and give them something to lose.
我去貧民區施捨點東西
Electricity, running water, school rooms for their kids.
電  自來水  學校教室
And for that taste of a better life,
讓他們嘗到了生活的甜頭
I own them.
我就控制了他們
Gentlemen.
各位乾杯
I apologize for the interruption.
抱歉打擾一下
Senior Reyes, may I speak with you?
雷耶斯老大  有事跟您報告
We've found them.
我們找到他們了
Pardon me, gentlemen.
失陪一下
Almost wish I didn't see that.
真希望我沒看到
Almost.
真希望
Wait, Dom.
等等  多姆
Mia was on that train.
當時米亞在火車上
My sister!
我妹在車上
I didn't know. I wouldn't do anything to hurt her.
我不知道  我不會傷害她
You set up the deal!
你自己接的生意
I thought the job was for the cars.
我以為只是偷車而已
I didn't know.
我之前不知道
All they want is the chip.
他們只想要芯片
Damn!
操
You should've come clean.
事先你怎麼不說清楚
What's going on out here?
你們在吵什麼
Nothing.
沒什麼
Please, Dom, just let me have the chip. I can take this to them.
拜託  多姆  把芯片給我  我給他們
They'll give it to Reyes and set things right.
我拿給雷耶斯  一切都結了
Get out.
滾
What?
什麼
You never listen to me.
你從來不聽我的
Not when I told you he was a cop,
那時我說他是個條子你不信
and not now.
現在還不信我
You never trust me and
你從不相信我
look where it's gotten us.
看看我們現在
Look at our family now.
看看我們幫派
I can't go home!
我有家不能回
Your sister is stuck in this life!
看你妹妹過的什麼日子
Where's Letty, Dom?
莉迪呢  多姆
Where's Letty?
莉迪呢
Plasma cutter.
離子切割機
Wilkes, I want a list of every place within 50 miles
威爾克斯  給我一份附近五十英里以內
that distributes compressed gas tanks.
運送壓縮氣罐的地點名單
Pass me that manifest.
把證物袋給我
Officer Neves. Been waiting for you.
奈維思警官  怎麼才來
- You asked for me? - I did.
-是你點名要我  -對
May I ask why?
為什麼
My smile is not that great.
我的笑容沒那麼好看
Your husband was an officer who was gunned down in the favela.
你丈夫是位警官  在貧民區被槍殺
Six months later, you upped and joined the force.
六個月後你振作起來加入了警隊
You're motivated.
你能保持幹勁
Plus, I figure you're the only one in Rio who cannot be bought.
而且 在堿蠽A是絕對不會被收買的人
Am I right?
我說得對嗎
- Yes. - Of course I am.
-是的  -當然
Good news, bad news.
喜憂參半
You know I like my dessert first.
說來聽聽
Back-checked the rail line like you asked.
我按你說的檢查了鐵路線
Found a couple of spots where they unloaded the cars.
發現幾個他們卸車的痕跡
One set of tracks headed west
一條往西
until it hit the main highway, then disappeared.
一直到主道才消失
But another set of tracks headed east.
另一條往東
A 107-inch wheelbase, eight-and-a-half-inch tread.
軸距一百七十英吋  輪胎印寬半英吋
The GT40 that was missing from the manifest.
是GT40嗎  從貨單上失蹤的那輛
Followed the trail a couple of miles.
留了幾公里車印
Pretty easy in this scrub.
這車很容易留印
Can't move without leaving a sign.
只要走動沒法不留痕
Give me the damn veggies.
把那該死的痕跡照給我
The ground rolls into a hardpack and we lost that track, too.
後來車開到硬地  胎印就沒了
Not necessarily.
也不一定
That road heads up through the hills into the favelas.
那條路穿過山丘通到貧民區
Couple of years ago, it was washed out by a storm.
幾年前被暴雨重開了
It's all dirt a mile from where you were.
經過那一公里車胎會粘上泥
If they headed that way, we'll pick up their tracks there.
往那邊走  就能追蹤到他們痕跡了
You come prepared.
有備而來啊
I'm motivated.
我幹勁十足
All right, then.
好了
Let's find ourselves a car.
我們這就去找
What do you think?
你覺得怎樣
Well, it's definitely a custom chip.
這芯片絕對不簡單
Look at all these side menus here for data entry.
看邊上這些輸入數據的菜單
Let's check this one.
看看這個
Look at that. Same building, same order every week.
看  同一幢大樓  每週一單
It's a delivery schedule.
交易時間表
What's this?
這是什麼
Drugs?
毒品嗎
No. That's a dealer pack.
不  交易量
See, most major players, they weigh their money
看  他們用這個貨量來算錢
so they don't have to constantly count it.
這樣就不用一點點的數了
Right there, that's 49 kilos.
那是四十九千克
49 kilos is a million in twenties.
在二十年代值一百萬
You're saying each one of these shipments is worth 10 million dollars?
你是說每批貨值一千萬
I thought so.
這才像話
So what is that?
那是什麼
A 100-million plus in cash houses?
一億鈔票的金庫嗎
That's how he keeps it off the grid.
這是查不到的交易憑證
I think it's safe to say that Reyes
雷耶斯不是傻子
is smart to want this back.
這東西不能落入他手
It's his whole network right there, just laid out on a chip.
芯片上就是他的交易網
Wilkes, Fusco, up the middle.
威爾克斯和富斯科去中路
Mac, Chato, flank north.
邁克  喬托  從北邊上
What about me?
我呢
Stay here.
待在這
Go that way!
去那邊
The other two went over the wall!
另外兩個翻牆了
Come on, go! Go!
快  快
Get on the ground.
趴下
I got Toretto. Four blocks north of your...
我抓到特若圖了  距4個房區...
They already know who you are.
他們知道你們是警察
Let's go.
我們走
You okay here?
你還好嗎
Yeah. I'm good. Thank you.
很好  謝謝
They're going to be looking for the three of us together now.
他們會把我們三個一鍋端
We need to split up.
我們得分開走
You and Mia head south, I'll lead them away.
你和米亞往南走  我把他們引開
No.
不
Dom is right.
多姆說得對
Look how lucky we just got. What happens next time?
這次我們僥倖逃脫  那下次呢
We have no choice but to split up.
我們只能分頭行動
I'm pregnant.
我懷孕了
I already lost my family once.
我失去過一次親人
I'm not going through that again.
我不想再失去了
- Are you kidding me? - No.
-你開玩笑嗎  -不是
I'm not going anywhere. Okay?
我哪也不去  好嗎
Dom?
多姆
Promise me we stick together.
答應我  我們一直在一起
I promise.
我答應
Our family just got bigger.
我們家族要添丁了
Something doesn't add up.
事有蹊蹺
Toretto and O'Conner. They stay when they're supposed to run,
特若圖和歐康納  能走卻沒走
they steal gas then give it away?
他們偷了東西  棄之不理
Now they're killing federal agents?
還殺了三個聯邦官員
It doesn't make any sense.
沒道理
Here's what makes sense.
道理在這
All these guys are is names on a list.
這些人都是逃犯
They come up, we take them down.
他們一出現  我們就拿下
Not a phone call more, not a bullet less.
不用報告  打光全部子彈
Wilkes, we get anything?
威爾克斯  有進展嗎
Standard forensics.
標準取證
Shoe prints. Hair and fiber.
鞋印  頭髮
Prints are all over the car.
車上儘是指紋
Anything else?
還有嗎
Yeah, we tracked the owner off the vehicle ID.
我們根據車的編碼查到了用戶信息
There are a couple of shell companies in between,
幾個空殼公司
but we finally traced it back to
最後發現這幾家公司都屬於
a corporation owned by an investor down here named Hernan Reyes.
投資人埃爾南·雷耶斯的電力集團
Investor?
投資人
If there is anything illegal happening in Rio, Reyes is involved.
堿讞狾釭澈D法交易  雷耶斯都有份
Okay, then so are we.
這樣我們也要插一腳了
If he could get us any closer to our guys,
他和我們有瓜葛了
I want everything on him.
那就查查他
Chato, you're on the roof.
喬托  去樓頂守著
I want you on overwatch in case somebody comes back for something.
防止有人返回報復
Mac, give me a cross-check on Reyes, full specs.
邁克  跟蹤監視雷耶斯
If he goes to the john,
看他見了什麼人
I want to know how many times he shakes it.
握了幾次手
You got it, boss.
知道了頭兒
Wilkes, Fusco!
威爾克斯  富斯科
Let's put all this mess back together.
來把這堆廢鐵組裝起來
That's going to take a while.
那得費不少工夫
Then you better get started.
那就趕緊的吧
They were taking this car apart for a reason.
他們憑白無故不會卸車
Let's put it back together and find out what's missing.
重新裝起來看少了什麼
Hey, Dom, what do you remember about your father?
多姆  你還記得你父親什麼樣嗎
My father.
我父親
He used to...
他以前
He used to have a barbecue every Sunday after church.
他以前會每週日做完禮拜後做燒烤
For anybody in the neighborhood.
鄰里街坊都來吃
If you didn't go to church, you didn't get any barbecue.
如果我們沒去做禮拜  就沒烤肉吃
Every single day he was in the shop,
每天白天他都在店
and every single night, he was at the kitchen table with Mia,
每個晚上他都在廚房桌子上
helping her with her homework.
輔導米亞做家庭作業
Even after she went to sleep, he'd stay up for a few more hours
就算她睡了  他也會再看幾個小時
so he could learn the next chapter and help her the next day.
學下一章明天再輔導她
I remember everything about my father.
我記得我父親的所有事
Everything.
所有事
That's just it.
算了
I don't remember shit about my dad.
我一點都不瞭解我爸
I don't remember him yelling.
我不記得他大吼大叫
I don't remember him smiling.
不記得他的笑容
To be honest with you,
說實話
I don't even remember what the hell he looked like.
我都不太記得他長什麼樣
I don't remember. He just...
我所有的記憶
He was just never there.
他總是不在
You ain't going to be like that, Brian.
你不會像他一樣的  布萊恩
We can't keep running, Dom.
我們不能逃下去了  多姆
We got to get out.
我們得金盆洗手
We got to get out now.
立刻馬上
You're right.
你說得對
Here's how we're going to do it.
我們這麼做
We're going to use this.
用這個東西
We're going do one last job.
幹上最後一票
We're going to take all of Reyes' money.
搞到雷耶斯所有的錢
Every dime of it,
一個銅板都不剩
and disappear.
然後永遠
Forever.
消失
New passports.
新護照
New lives with no more looking over our shoulder.
新生活   再不東躲西藏
And we're just going to buy our freedom.
我們就自由了
That's right.
沒錯
You realize
你想過沒
we're talking about going up against the most powerful guy in all of Rio?
我們這次是要對抗堿貜漲悀j
Yes, we are.
是的  我知道
Then we're going to need a team.
那麼就要招兵買馬
Let's run through the bases real quick. Who do we got?
那我們好好想想 都招誰
First we're going to need a chameleon.
首先  一個多面手
Someone who can blend in anywhere.
處處深藏不露
What else?
還有呢
A fast talker.
大忽悠
Someone who can bullshit their way out of anything.
一張嘴走遍天下
I got that.
我認識一個
This guy is going to have a lot of surveillance.
他們有很多監控設備
We're going to need someone who is good with circuits.
需要一個人搞定這些監控
And with those circuits,
除了監控
Reyes is going to have wells.
雷耶斯一定有個保險箱
We're going to need guys to punch through those walls.
還需要人手破解保險箱
What else?
然後呢
Utilities and weapons.
火力掩護
Someone who ain't afraid to throw down.
一個不俱危險的
Someone to back up every position.
全能型後援
Yeah, what else do we need?
還需要別的嗎
Most importantly,
最重要的
we're going to need two precision drivers.
兩個穩妥的車手
Guys that don't crack under pressure.
關鍵時刻不會掉鏈子
Guys that never lose.
永不放棄
You know we got that.
車手  你我都有數了
Aw, hell, no!
不是吧
I see they really scraped the bottom of the barrel, huh?
這次還真是興師動眾
I guess they did, since your ass is here.
你這貨都來了  那一定是
When are you going to give Martin Luther King his car back?
你打算什麼時候把馬丁·路德·金的車開回來
As soon as you give Rick James his jacket back.
等你拿來瑞克·詹姆斯的夾克再說
What's up, man?
過的怎麼樣  老兄
Sexy legs, baby girl.
長腿妹
What time do they open?
啥時候伺候哥一下
They open the same time as I pull this trigger.
在我扣下扳機之後
Want me to open them?
還想讓我伺候你嗎
I told you the skinny chick had balls.
告訴過你這個美腿妞兒不好惹
Looks like she started the party without us.
看起來她已經自己找到樂子了
Hey, anybody can talk shit in Spanish, homie.
兄弟  西班牙語怎麼罵人
What's this guy saying?
這哥們說什麼呢
Ugly is still ugly in Spanish or in English.
長得醜說啥語都沒用
- Who are these clowns, man? - Circus clowns.
-這兩個小丑是誰  -馬戲團來的吧
I thought cockfights were illegal in Brazil.
我還以為巴西鬥雞犯法呢
I see you all have met.
都互相認識了吧
You know when you called me to come to Rio
你叫我來堿貜漁伬
I assumed it would be for something more exciting than this.
我以為是比這更有意思的事兒呢
Look at this guy.
來了夥計
- Long time. - I missed you, man.
-好久不見  -想死你了
Good to see you.
見到你真好
Brother. What's up?
兄弟  啥事
Yo, check this out. This is Tej.
認識一下  這是泰基
Best circuit man on the East Coast.
東海岸最厲害的萬能電工
And this is my boy, Roman Pearce.
我的老朋友羅曼·皮爾斯
We go way back, I met this guy in juvie.
老交情了  我在少管所認識的
I pulled that job with him in Miami.
邁阿密那票就是和他聯手干的
I've heard about you.
久仰大名
Nice digs.
選對人了
Yeah, well, the Ritz was sold out.
是  沒有別人了
So what's this all about, Dom?
那現在是什麼情況
Yeah, man, why did you drag us halfway around the world?
你折騰我們橫跨了半個地球為了什麼
Because we got a job.
有筆買賣
All right, so our target's name is Hernan Reyes.
目標名叫埃爾南·雷耶斯
And he runs the drug scene down here.
這堛漪r梟
He's never been busted because he doesn't leave a paper trail.
他從未落馬  因為不留書面字據
No paper trail means no banks.
那就是說錢不通過銀行
And no banks means cash houses.
存在現金倉庫
That's right. Ten of them, to be exact.
說得對  總共十家金庫
Spread throughout the city.
分散在城內
And we're going to hit them all.
我們要把錢都拿走
All of them?
所有嗎
All of them.
對
That sounds crazy.
太瘋狂了
You bring us to a whole other country
叫我們來異國他鄉
so we can rob the dude who runs it?
還要去搶劫這堛漲悀j
I thought this was business.
我以為只是筆買賣
Sounds personal to me.
但更像是私人恩怨
Is that what this is?
就這事嗎
I got love for y'all,
我愛你們大家
but personal ain't good business.
但是私人恩怨的生意真的不好做
I can't do this, homie.
我覺得我幹不了
So what we're talking about is $100 million.
這次生意是個一億美元的大單
You say what?
你說什麼
Hundred... See, sometimes I be over thinking, man,
你看  我有時候想得比較多
and I know we just met, but you just, kind of, got to...
可能是  我們剛認識  但是
That's right, $100 million, and everything we take,
對  一億  拿多少
we split even.
就分多少
That's a little over $11 million apiece.
每人一千一百萬
I am down.
砸死我吧
I'm in.
我加入
Eleven million.
一千一百萬
Sounds like a whole lot of vaginal activity to me.
像成千上萬女人對我投懷送抱
You can't pull off 10 heists on the same mark.
你不可能同時搶十家
You just can't.
完全沒可能
As soon as we hit the first one,
對  我們搶了第一個
they're going to do everything they can to protect the rest.
他們就會拚命保護其他幾個
Exactly.
沒錯
Nobody move!
都別動
That's all of it.
都在這了
You a dead man.
你們死定了
You're all dead men!
你們都死定了
You don't have a place to hide.
你們無處可藏
Who's hiding?
誰要藏了
Are you crazy?
你們瘋了嗎
Do you know whose house this is?
知道這是誰的地方嗎
Whose money are you stealing?
知道偷的是誰的錢嗎
We ain't stealing it.
我們不偷
You tell your boss exactly who did this.
給你老闆帶個話  告訴他誰幹的
Tell him there's more coming.
告訴他這還不算完
Voila.
好啦
Turn it over.
發動它
She's running on all eight. Checks out fine.
運轉正常  沒問題
Keep looking.
接著找
Boss, if something was missing, we'd know.
頭兒  如果少了什麼東西我們會知道的
It's a goddamn shame putting bullshit like that on a classic.
這東西出現在這種跑車上太低級
You may as well slap neon lights on it.
還可以用
They took the chip.
他們把芯片拿走了
We got a hit on the police scanner.
警方監視器發現情況
Armed robbery at a house in Leblon.
黎布朗一處倉庫發生武裝搶劫
Address cross-checks against property
地址核查得出
owned by one of Hernan Reyes' corporations.
正是雷耶斯公司財產
All right, if that's our guys
好吧  如果是我們追捕的那夥人
then whatever was on that chip led them directly to that house.
一定是芯片上的內容引導他們去的那
It's them, for sure.
肯定是他們
How do you know that?
你怎麼知道
Because no one else in Rio is stupid enough to rob Reyes.
因為在堿蠿S人傻到去搶雷耶斯
Explain.
給我解釋
They invaded the Leblon house.
他們侵入了黎布朗的倉庫
Who invaded?
誰
The men from the train.
火車上的那些人
How much did they take?
他們拿走多少錢
They didn't take anything.
一分也沒拿
They burned it!
他們把錢燒了
They burned my money?
他們燒了我的錢
Yes. And said there's more coming.
是的  還說這還不算完
Okay...
好吧
Then this...
那麼
...is what we're going to do.
我們這麼做
Clean the houses.
清理所有金庫
I want that money under lock and key...
我要那筆錢在
...within an hour.
一小時內鎖好
Understand?
明白嗎
Understood.
明白
Number One is on the move, man.
一號出動了
Two is on the move.
二號上路了
I got mine.
我跟上了
I got eyes on Five.
五號盯上
I know y'all said they were consolidating the money somewhere, but,
你們都說  他會把錢轉移到某處
y'all ain't going to believe this.
但是你絕沒想到這一點
Well, this job just got a lot harder.
難度增加了
If he's moving it into a police station
他既然能把錢放到警察局
he's got some serious brass in his pocket.
說明他肯定認識高層人物
Looks like this is going to be a shorter trip than I thought...
看起來我們要提前收場了
Hell, yeah, we can't do this.
太對了  這活兒沒法干
"Can't"'? You mean, "Shouldn't."
沒法干  或者說不該干
I think this doesn't change a thing.
我覺得沒什麼影響
I say we stick to the plan.
按計劃進行
You say what?
你說什麼
This just went from Mission: Impossible
這破活已經從不可能
to Mission: In-freaking-sanity.
變成瘋子才去做
Whatever, man.
隨便吧夥計
I ain't scared, I'm just letting you all know,
我不是害怕  就是提醒你們一下
going in that building is crazy.
進去就是瘋子
I got this.
這我知道
What time was the robbery?
幾點發生的搶劫
11:00.
十一點左右
Here we go.
找到了
Enhance it.
放大
Their faces are covered.
臉被遮住了
Run it through FRS.
面部識別
Well, hello, you son of a bitch.
好啊  王八蛋
Wilkes!
威爾克斯
Run the photos of known associates of Toretto and O'Conner
把特若圖和歐康納關係網堛熒茪
against customs entries into Brazil in the last two weeks.
和最近兩周入關巴西的人進行比對
Check planes, trains, boats,
檢查海陸空
everything short of the goddamn space shuttle.
和除了航天飛機的一切運輸設備
They can change their names but they can't change their faces.
他們能換個名字  但是換不了臉
Something big is going down.
他們一定在計劃什麼
That's a 1970 Charger.
這是輛一九七零年的Charger[著名肌肉車]
Fusco! Upload these specs into the database.
富斯科  上傳這些信息到電腦數據庫
Have the computer cross-check it with overhead satellites
與衛星每十五分鐘交叉核對一次
every 15 minutes, the van behind it, too.
及時更新
If these vehicles move in the streets of Rio,
如果這些車行駛在堿貜熊颿欴
I want to know about it.
我希望能得到消息
Everything okay?
一切都好嗎
Everything is okay.
一切順利
Who is this Hobbs? This Federal Agent running around town?
這個滿街跑霍布斯探員何方神聖
Some American cowboy.
美國人
He's handled.
在我們掌控之中
He killed sixteen of our men.
他殺了我們十六個人
Handle him better.
盯緊點兒他
Look... He requested a rookie patrol officer as his assistant.
他要了一個菜鳥巡邏隊長做助手
They won't be a problem.
他們不是問題
- It's all here?- Yes.
-都在這嗎  -對
What about Toretto and O'Conner? Where are they?
特若圖和歐康納呢  他們在哪
Nothing yet.
還沒消息
But I have all our officers searching.
但我把人手都派出去找他們了
Not good enough.
這還不夠
Put a price on their heads.
懸賞緝拿
High enough...
出個高價
...to get every pair of eyes in the city searching for them.
讓城堥C雙眼睛都找給我找
The beauty of public offices?
警署內部圖
Public records.
公共檔案室
This is where he's keeping the money.
這是他們放錢的地方
The vault in the evidence room.
保險箱在證物室
Um. Uh, yeah. Can I get everyone's attention,
麻煩大家注意一下
right here, for a second?
這邊  耽誤會兒
We're talking about breaking into a police station.
我們正在討論如何闖入警察局
Is anyone listening to those words?
你們聽說過這些詞嗎
Anybody? Popo?
警察叔叔
Five-O. One-time. Pigs.
條子  雷子  當兵的
People we don't like.
都是我們的死對頭
You know, police stations are designed to keep people in, not out.
警察局的設計  就是讓人進去出不來
That's why it's a stealth mission.
所以我們要秘密行動
We'll be in and out before they even know we were there.
沒等人反應過來  我們就完活兒了
Well, we'll need to get eyes in there.
我們需要瞭解那堶悸滷〞p
At least to find out the make and model of that vault.
至少要知道這金庫有多大
So the vault and then, so...
這大金庫...
it's crazy.
很瘋狂
Who's supposed to do all this?
誰適合幹這些
What do you mean?
你們什麼意思
Why me?
為什麼是我
Because you got the biggest mouth.
因為你最會說話
That's for damn sure.
太對了
Hello, beautiful.
你好美女
Look at those dimples. Sexy, sexy.
性感的小酒窩
Love those glasses. Where did you get them from?
眼鏡真可愛  在哪買的
Are those like Gucci frames or something?
鏡框是古琦的嗎
No English?
不會英語嗎
No, no, no. Damn.
不  該死
How are you, sir?
你誰呀
Special Agent O'Conner. US Federal Bureau of Investigation.
美國聯邦調查局特工歐康納
It says Caucasian.
你白種人嗎
That's a tan. You know, a tan?
那個  這是曬黑的  曬的
Look, I'm working this
你看  我負責這個案子
case and I got some evidence here to be held.
有些證物要放到證物室
But I need to get in and check your storage facility first.
但是我要先進去檢查你的儲存設備
Nope.
不行
Look, I know you're a true professional,
我知道你非常敬業
and I respect you, I promise.
我敬佩你  都是真心話
You know, it looks like you work out a little bit, too.
你有時也鍛煉吧
What do you bench, about 350?
能舉起三百五十磅嗎
Ah, Shit.
該死
Look, I'm just trying to do my job, man.
我也只是奉命而已
My boss sent me here to just make sure that everything was safe.
我的頭兒讓我來確保東西都安全
It will be safe.
都很安全
Let me just come in and take a quick peek.
好吧  那你能讓我進去簡單看一眼嗎
Nope.
不行
Come on, man. Hook a brother up, please?
通融一下夥計  放兄弟一馬吧
Nope. And you're not my brother.
不行  你才不是我兄弟
Brother from another mother?
同父異母的兄弟
Look!
聽好了
No one enters the facility but authorized evidence personnel.
未經授權任何人不能進入
Now stop wasting my time.
少耽誤工夫
I'm going to call the embassy.
我要給大使館打電話了
No,no,no! No, we're good.
別別別  沒事了
We don't need to call them. For what? We're good.
沒必要打電話  不至於
Here, I got the box. We're all good.
給你  東西放這了 沒事了
I promise you. Thank you so much for your time.
我保證  非常感謝
Swear to God, if you were on the other side of that glass
我發誓如果我在玻璃那一面
I'd bust your damn face in. Now translate that.
我就打爆你的臉  好好表示一下
It's done. See, I think I
完活兒
make a better special agent than you ever did.
我當特工比你強
Well, that depends on how you define "Special."
那要看你哪方面更特一點
Come on, now. Let's see what we got.
各位  該看好戲了
Not funny.
別鬧
All right, come on.
好吧
Dawg, you still can't drive.
你還是不會開車
Now, I see why you're always getting into accidents.
看吧 現在我知道你為什麼總出事故了
You can't even drive a damn remote control car.
你連輛破遙控車都開不好
I'm going to need you to shut up right now.
你馬上閉嘴
- I'm not going to shut up. - Shut up.
-才不  -閉嘴
Strap him in his safety belt, man.
快把他嘴上的堵上
Give me the remote, dawg. Go left.
給我遙控器  往左
It looks like something
左邊好像有東西
right over there to the left. What is that?
那是什麼
Bingo.
找到了
What is that, six-by-six?
這是什麼  六乘六的嗎
Eight-by-twelve.
八乘十二的
Seven-by-twelve.
七乘十二
Fitted with 18-inch-thick steel reinforced walls
十八英吋厚的加固鋼板
with a insulated copper core to protect against thermal lance.
用絕緣銅芯線抵禦高溫焊槍
A Class-3 electronic lock with a surefire Griffin retumbler
先進的三級電子鎖
and a biometric palm scanner.
和生物掌紋掃瞄系統
Ten tons of top-of-the-line security.
十倍於頂級線路安全設計
Do I want to know how you know all that?
你怎麼知道的這麼清楚
I had a life before you knew me, O'Conner.
誰都有過去  歐康納
Let's just leave it at that, all right?
這個以後再說
She is a beauty, though, man.
她可真漂亮
A "Beauty" As in "Good"?
是褒義的漂亮嗎
"Beauty" As in, she's going to start off playing hard to get.
漂亮的意思是  她很難搞定
Then, no matter how much I caress her,
而且  不管我怎樣愛撫她
no matter how much I love her,
怎樣愛她
in the end, she still ain't going to give up that ass.
最終還是不會從了我
Two to one says you blow the wrong pipe.
大家都說你炸錯了管道
Yo, why you got to be so negative all the time, man?
你為什麼總抱怨呢
I ain't negative.
我沒啊
I'm just positive you're going to mess it up.
我就是堅信你會把事情搞糟
I'm telling you, man, you got issues.
下次如果沒有電梯的話我絕對不來
You need to learn to relax, loco.
你要學會放鬆
You better hurry up, we got less than a minute.
你最好快點  時間不到一分鐘了
Why do you always set the timer so short?
為什麼你總把時間設置的這麼短
I hope you know where you're going.
希望你知道要往哪走
I got this. Relax, man.
我明白  放鬆  放鬆
Relax.
放鬆
...A police station.
警局
You used too much explosive! Again.
你炸藥又用多了
Too much, too little...
多少
it's all the same.
都一樣
That's some Buddha shit you
這又是你從監獄圖書館
learned from a book in the prison library, isn't it?
學的狗屁佛家理論吧
And what you're doing there on the wall...
你在牆上幹的事
You got that from the same book, huh?
也是從那本書上學的吧
You're so negative, bro.
你又抱怨了
Can I have some light?
給個亮
Got it. We got it!
收到  收到了
Yeah, we're looking at four cameras.
好的  我們收到四個探頭的信號
Yo, that's some high-end shit, too. Marker optics.
又是些高端的光學儀器
Hundred-degree field-of-view. Ten seconds oscillation.
每十秒來回擺動一次
Yeah, that's a narrow window, man.
不是吧  擺動太快了
Can't we just tap in and replace the image?
我們不能用靜態圖片代替嗎
No, it's hooked into a digital sync.
不行  它是和系統同步的
They would know we were in the system.
肯定會被識別出來
The best we can do is peek.
最好就是一閃而過
We're going to need some real fast cars to get through this.
我們得用非常快的車來幹這件事
Not just fast.
而且不只車要快
You got a hard right and a hairpin.
還需要高超的駕駛技巧和練習
We're going to need something agile.
必須開得敏捷又靈活
You guys mock up a track.
你們幾個畫出一個跑道
O'Conner.
歐康納
Let's go get some cars.
咱們去找幾輛車
Nice.
爽
Home sweet home.
舒服  真舒服
Or that.
那個
How about that? All motor, no tuning issues.
那輛怎麼樣  引擎聲相當完美
I always wanted one of those.
我一直想要一輛那樣的
Held the record on the Avenida three years running.
恩威達大賽三年的紀錄保持者
Damn, bro...
該死
You got a lot of balls to bring your problems here, Toretto.
你來這真是自找麻煩  特若圖
Not to mention a cop.
還帶著個條子
Yeah, we can keep that on the low.
咱們可以保持低調
Word on the street is a lot of people are looking for you two.
都說很多人在找你們倆
What?
啥
You didn't think we'd recognize you?
你沒想過我們會認出你們嗎
No, we're kind of counting on it.
你們有什麼車
That little coupe may run the streets around here,
那輛小跑可能走街串巷吃得開
but that monster has never seen a set of tail lights.
但是那位大哥還從沒看過別的車的尾燈呢
Even Well, she's about to.
馬上就會了
Dominic Toretto's ride in my garage.
多米尼克·特若圖  來我這賽車了
Now that... will be a nice trophy.
那輛車  是輛不錯的戰利品
Let's go, legend.
來吧  傳奇
Car for car.
以車賭車
You want it, come and get it.
想要  就來比比
Let's see what they got.
大伙瞧瞧
Really?
真的假的
Where did you get that from? Papa Smurf?
你在哪弄到的  波巴的市場媔
Okay, O'Conner, give it your best shot.
來吧歐康納  使出你的看家本事
How was that one?
怎麼樣
Camera caught you.
探頭照到你了
- What? - Yeah, it still caught you.
-什麼  -沒錯  找到了
Man, I was milking the hell out of that thing, too.
看來我得開得更快才行
We're going to need a faster car.
我們需要更快的車
I want my money. Come on, man.
我需要那筆錢
Let's get it! Watch this.
來吧  看這個
That's exactly why your ass ain't been driving.
這就能解釋你為什麼不開車
I think I'm in love.
我想  我戀愛了
That was real solid work.
技術絕對一流
I think Camera 3 still caught you, though.
但是三號探頭還是抓到你了
Let's do it again.
再來一遍
That's the piggy bank you ordered.
這是你訂製的存錢罐嗎
You're kidding me. Yep.
太搞笑了
Where in the hell did y'all get one of these?
你從哪媟d到的
Well, we had a life before you met us.
好吧  誰都有過去
All right, I'll get to work on the electronic tumbler
好吧  我來搞定電子鎖
but there's still another problem.
但是還有個問題
Palm scanner.
掌紋掃瞄系統
And without Reyes' handprint,
沒有雷耶斯的掌紋
Houdini himself couldn't open this bitch.
胡迪尼[世界最著名魔術師]都打不開
How do you know it's Reyes' handprint?
你怎麼知道一定是雷耶斯本人的掌紋
You got $100 million in a safe.
如果堶悸漱@億美元是你的
You going to put somebody else's handprint on it?
你會用別人的掌紋來做密碼嗎
That shit is eating you alive.
這玩意要弄死你了
You check that.
試試
- Yo, check that. - Shut up!
-試試  -閉嘴
How are we supposed to get Reyes' handprint?
我們怎麼搞到雷耶斯的掌紋
Han.
韓
You're up.
你來
Sure. Nothing like the easy stuff.
沒問題  小事一樁
Let's go. I'll drive.
我也去  我開車
- I make six bodyguards. - Seven.
-有六個保鏢  -七個
You think that guy with a fanny pack is a tourist?
你覺得那個一臉怪相的人是遊客嗎
So, how long were you in the army?
你在軍隊待了多久
That gun you pulled the other day was a Jericho 941.
你那天用的Jericho 941[手槍型號]
Thumb-racking the slide?
快速上膛
That was straight-up Mossad.
摩薩德[以色列情報和特殊使命局]的招式
I got out of the military
你戒煙的時候
probably the same time you quit smoking.
我就退伍了
The amount of chips you eat,
你吃那麼多薯片
the way you always have to keep your hands and mouth busy,
嘴還閒不住是嗎
you were a two-pack-a-day man for sure.
你以前一天肯定抽兩包
Unfiltered.
無濾嘴的
Well, this is a bust.
這次沒戲
We're not going to be able to get his fingerprints out here.
拿不到雷耶斯的掌紋
We need to do some more recon, call in a couple of extra guys.
還得多做點偵察  再找幾個幫手
Or
或者
you don't send a man to do a woman's job.
有些事兒注定要女人來做
We're going to figure this out, I promise you.
我們能搞定  我保證
What's up?
怎麼了
I thought you were more of a thong man.
原來你也不是什麼正人君子
We got the print.
弄到掌紋了
Where?
在哪
Okay, that's crazy.
這太扯了
So, did he just slap that ass or did he grab and hold on to it?
他就拍了一下你的屁股  還是整個抓住
Hey, this will work.
這個能用
I'm impressed.
我看好你哦
- Got it? - Got it.
-行嗎  -可以
But you still didn't answer the question.
可你還沒回答呢
Oh, no. Guys, guys! Guys, we have a problem.
夥計們  有麻煩了
The whole team just got burnt.
我們都暴露了
Now we're all wanted.
我們被通緝了
How did this happen?
怎麼會
US Diplomatic Security Service issued the warrants.
美國外交安全局已經授權
Agent L. Hobbs.
霍布斯探員
Hold on one second.
等等
Hey, Dom.
多姆
Is that the guy you saw in the favela?
這人是你在貧民區見過的那個嗎
Yeah.
是的
Hobbs is the leader of the elite task force for the DSS.
霍布斯是Dss精英特遣隊長
So he's good.
就是說  他很厲害嗎
When the FBI wants to find somebody, that's who they call.
FBI想抓人的時候就派他出馬
Because he never misses his mark.
因為他從未失手
This guy is Old Testament.
這傢伙是個傳奇人物
Blood, bullets, wrath of God. That's his style.
鐵血硬漢是他的一貫作風
And right now he's hunting us?
而且此時此刻他正在找我們
Dom, we got to move up our timeline.
多姆  我們得加快進度了
Yeah, but how?
好的  但是怎麼來
This thing's already been
這件事已經很困難了
difficult without Wyatt Earp on our asses.
如果他再摻合進來
If anything, we need more room to breathe.
我們需要更多的喘息空間
Roman's right.
羅曼說的沒錯
Think we need to get some fresh air.
我們出去透透氣
We've got a hit. '70s Charger.
找到了  70年代的Charger
Let's get a move on!
出發
Eastbound on Avenida Atlantica.
向安維尼迪拉卡街區東部行駛
Move, move, move, move!
快快快
It stopped about a block ahead.
他在前面一個街區停下了
Park it. We're going on foot.
停車  我們步行過去
Hey, Toretto.
特若圖
You're under arrest.
你被捕了
Arrest?
被捕?
I don't feel like I'm under arrest.
我看不是吧
How about you, Brian?
你覺得呢布萊恩
No, not a bit.
不  沒有
Not even a little bit.
一點都沒有
Just give it a minute. It'll sink in.
我給你們一分鐘  看能不能想明白
We didn't kill those feds. That was Reyes.
我們沒殺那些聯邦探員  雷耶斯干的
I don't give a shit.
我不管這個
I'm just here to bring in two assholes whose names hit my desk.
我聽命抓兩個混蛋歸案
Yeah, that sounds like a real hero.
聽起來像真英雄
That's funny.
真搞笑
From a guy who took the oath of a cop,
這話出自一個警察
then went against everything it stood for.
他忘掉先前的誓言
Or some wannabe tough guy prick
一個硬漢
who beat a man half to death with a socket wrench.
原來用電棍懲治惡徒
Yeah, real tough.
還真是條好漢
You turn around and put your hands behind your back.
現在轉身雙手放在背後
I don't think so.
我不會這麼做
Your mistake is thinking you got a goddamn choice, boy.
小子  你以為自己有的選嗎
And your mistake?
你搞錯了把
Thinking you're in America.
還以為自己在美國啊
You're a long way from home.
你離家可遠著呢
This is Brazil.
這是巴西
Come on, boss. Another day.
算了  頭兒  改天吧
Come on, H, it's a lot of heat.
算了  今天不是時候
I'll see you soon, Toretto.
後會有期  特若圖
I look forward to it, cop.
隨時奉陪
Yep.
好了
Tracker's on.
追蹤器裝好了
Got them.
找到了
I don't understand. Why come here?
我不明白  來幹什麼
Why risk it all for $20 worth of silver?
為了一個二十美元的銀飾值得嗎
Because it's worth it.
它值得
You should run, you know.
你該逃走
Hobbs will find you.
霍布斯會抓到你的
You have every reason to leave. Why stay?
你有一萬個理由離開  為什麼不呢
Why do you?
你又是為什麼呢
My husband was a good police officer.
我丈夫是個好警員...
An honest man.
老實人...
We both grew up here.
我們青梅竹馬
Two years ago he was murdered in the street
兩年前  他在街上被謀殺了
right outside our door.
就在我們家門外
Reyes owns this favela now. He gives things to people.
這堿O雷耶斯的地盤  他給大家東西
But everything has a price.
而東西不是白給的
The people here need a new start.
這堛漱H們需要一個新的開始
They need to be free.
需要自由
You didn't kill those men in the train,
火車上那些人不是你殺的
did you?
對嗎
Now, why would you believe anything I would tell you?
你現在怎麼又相信我了呢
Was she so special to you?
她對你來說真的那麼特別嗎
I never thought anyone could understand now much.
我以為沒有人能夠理解
But you do.
但是你懂我了
Close, but not enough.
差不多  但還不夠好
Dom, the window is too small, man.
夥計  時間太短了
Only way we're going to beat the cameras is with invisible cars.
唯一能躲過攝像頭的辦法就是用隱形車了
And I know just where to get them.
我正好知道這麼個地方
Let's take a ride, boys.
夥計們  出去兜個風吧
Don't hurt yourself.
別傷著自己
It's been a while since
我已經好久沒有
I've been behind the wheel of one of these.
駕駛過警車了
First time I've ever been in the front seat.
我也是第一次坐警車前座
Rome, what took you so long?
羅曼  怎麼耽擱這麼久
I thought for sure you'd be
我剛打包票你一定會
showing up with some chrome spinners or something.
裝個鉻紡輪還是什麼登場的
Real funny.
真搞笑
I got $100,000 that says
我賭十萬美金
I can take you all in the next quarter-mile.
我比你們都先到下下個路口
Yeah, your broke ass has got a hundred grand.
你說的像真有十萬塊似的
If we pull off this job, I will.
如果我們這次幹成了  我就有了
The next two lights.
下兩個紅綠燈
Hundred thousand.
十萬塊
We don't pull this job off, we're probably dead anyway.
如果我們這次干砸了  反正也死翹翹了
Let's make it a million.
我們賭一百萬吧
I like that. All right, a million-dollar quarter-mile.
我贊成  一百萬賭四分之一英里
All right, then.
好的
You only live once. Let's do it.
人生只有一次 來吧
What do you say, Dom?
多姆  你說呢
We talking or we racing?
到底要聊天呢還是要賽車
Just don't cheat this time.
這次別作弊了啊
Got to let that go.
你就是不能忘了這茬
Typical, Roman.
還是老樣子  羅曼
I'm going to get this money. I'm hungry.
我需要這筆錢  我贏定了
Don't make it too easy for me, boys.
別讓我贏得太容易  夥計們
No!
沒門
Not this time, Dom.
那可沒準  多姆
You got to want it, Brian.
加把勁兒  布萊恩
Yeah! Owned you! Owned you!
我贏了  贏了
- Good race, O'Conner. - Thanks, Dom.
-開得不錯  歐康納  -承讓
Do you know how long I've been waiting for that shit?
你們知道我等這天多久了嗎
I told you he didn't see it.
我就說  他沒看出來吧
Your man right there?
你沒看出來嗎
He let off the throttle at the line.
他最後關頭鬆了油門
You didn't do nothing. He let you win.
你沒贏  他讓你的
Bullshit.
胡扯
- Vince, what are you doing? - Quiet! They've been tracking you.
-文森  你要做什麼 -別說話  有人跟蹤
I know she's here!
我知道那個女的在這
Find her!
去找
Go!Go!Go!
快去
It's okay. Wait!
沒事  等等
Reyes' guys were waiting for me at the market.
雷耶斯的人在市場埋伏我
Vince saved my life.
文森救了我
You hungry?
餓不餓
- Yeah, sure. - Good.
-正好餓了  -不錯
Because you're saying grace.
今天還算客氣
Thanks, Vince.
謝了  文森
Yo, you burned it!
你把它烤焦了
Yo, this is how my momma does it. Relax.
我媽就這麼弄  放鬆
Yeah, but your mom is the worst cook in the world.
是的  但是你媽是世上最差的廚子
Yo, don't you be talking about my momma.
不許說我老媽
Yeah, come on, baby. Who's good living?
干一個  生活不錯
To you, bro. Cheers, cheers, cheers.
乾杯  乾杯  乾杯
So, we in Brazil. It's the good life.
我們在巴西  活的還不錯
So, you got a little more than $10 or $11 million coming.
你有  有了一千還是一千一百多萬後
What you going to do with your money?
打算怎麼花
- Me? - Yeah.
-我嗎 -是的
Actually, man, I been
事實上  我一直想著
thinking about opening up a garage back home.
回家開一個修車廠
Place where people can bring their cars and
顧客把車開來
not get completely ripped off.
只賺一點點就好
You know what I mean?
你明白不
- Really? - Yeah.
-真的嗎 -是的
So, your dream is to start a day job?
那麼  你的夢想就是白天幹活
That's stupid. Like, why would...
這  這真蠢  夥計  為什麼
No, it's not stupid at all. I love what I do.
不...這一點也不蠢  我喜歡幹這個
That don't make no sense to me.
那有啥意思
I know what I'm going to do with my money.
你們想知道我怎麼花嗎
Buying some cooking lessons for my man.
為我男人找個廚師班
See? See?
看到沒
There you go with that negativity, man.
你又開始抱怨這個了
You know me. Money ain't a goddamn thing.
你瞭解我  我不在乎錢
It's going to take a little more than money to learn how to cook.
光交學費  學不會做飯
That's horrible.
那真糟糕
But I heard they was looking
我聽說動物收容所
for a chef down at this animal shelter.
正在找個廚子
You might want to...
你想不想
I know the manager.
我認識經理
Hey, Dom.
你好  多姆
Listen.
聽著
I know that you're all set for this job tomorrow,
我知道你明天要幹一票
but if you need an extra man, I could...
如果還缺人手
You're in.
麥克  你也有份
There's always room for family.
一家人不說兩家話
Thank you.
謝謝
Get something to eat.
吃點東西去
Yeah.
好
Can you believe Mia calls this a curse?
米亞稱它為詛咒
She might be right.
她或許是對的
You really like doing that stuff, huh?
你真的挺喜歡做這個的
When your life is on the line
生死攸關之時
that's when you learn about yourself.
只能靠自己
That's a fair deal.
這是個公平交易
We're less than 24 hours
距離我們人生最大的慶祝
from the biggest celebration of our life.
不到二十四小時了
Y'all need a refill. This is serious stuff.
你們得充充電  這是很嚴肅的事
- No, I'm good. - Cheers, baby.
-不了  -喝一個
I'm good. No, thank you.
不  不用了  不了  謝謝
No, she can't.
不  她不能喝
What do you mean? She can't.
什麼意思  她不能喝
Are you serious right now?
你不是在開玩笑吧
Is that the reason you let him beat you in the quarter-mile?
這就是你讓他跑贏你的原因嗎
- That was a baby gift. - No, that's messed up.
-是給寶寶的禮物  -才不是
No, you're not taking that from me.
你說什麼都是我贏了
Wait, wait, hold on a second.
等等  等等  等一下
So, did he just smack the ass or did he grab and hold on to it?
他是拍了一下你的屁股  還是整個抓住
Which One was it?
哪一種
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
-恭喜  -謝謝
How can you keep this a secret?
為什麼藏著不告訴我們
Crazy, huh?  It's your boy.
你小子都有兒子了
Baby gift, huh?
給寶寶的禮物
I have no idea what they're talking about.
我不知道他們在說什麼
Toast
致敬
Money will come and go. We know that.
錢財乃身外之物
But the most important thing
生命中最寶貴永遠是
in life will always be the people in this room.
這個房間堛漣A們
Right here.
此時
Right now.
此地
I'm all set.
我準備好了
Yo, Santos. Van good?
桑托斯  都好了嗎
You know we're always good, bro.
是的  我隨時就緒  兄弟
Hobbs is on the other side of the city.
霍布斯他們在城市另一頭
We're not going to get a better window.
這是最佳時機
Okay, guys, it's show time!
來吧  夥計們  該我們上場了
First team in position, let's go.
第一隊就位  出發
Come on, let's do this.
快點  出發
Hey, Dom.
多姆
I got eyes on Mia.
我會照顧米亞的
Moscow, Bali, Goa, Hong Kong.
莫斯科  巴厘  果阿邦  香港
And what do they all have in common?
他們有什麼共同點
No extradition.
不能引渡
We're one hour away from the rest of our lives.
我們還有一小時就可以去了
Cops!
警察
Come on. Go.
快點  跑
You just made a big mistake.
你剛真是大錯特錯了
Took me a while to find that tracking chip.
找到追蹤芯片是費了我點時間
But not as long to flip the receiver.
但是  找接收器可不用那麼久
You're going down, Toretto.
特若圖  你完了
I'm right here.
老子奉陪到底
- Dom! Stand back. - I got this.
-多姆  退後 -我來搞定
- Pull off! - Dom! Please, stop!
-住手  -多姆  住手
Dom!
多姆
We're coming in now.
我們正在回來的路上
Have the marshals meet us at the airport when we land.
派警隊去機場接我們
Ambush!
有埋伏
Wilkes, suppression fire. Shut them down.
威爾克斯  反擊  搞定他們
Stagger-step. Cover me.
掩護我
Watch them!
看著那邊
Cut us loose!
放開我們
Come on! Cut us loose!
快點  放開我們
- We're good? - Yeah, let's go, let's go!
-都上來了嗎  -開車
Hey, Dom.
多姆
You've got to meet my son.
你還沒見過我兒子
Nico.
尼克
I will.
我會見到的
He's a good kid.
他是個好孩子
You know, we named him after you.
我們用你的名字給他命名的
"Dominic."
多米尼克
You've got my word, Vince.
我向你保證  文森
You were always my brother.
你一直是我的兄弟
I got eyes on Nico now.
我幫你養兒子
We need to move. We don't have that much time.
我們得走了  沒有多少時間了
I got us a flight out.
我訂了趟航班跑路
We can leave Rio in the rearview in the next five hours.
五小時後離開里約熱內盧
Not to run away.
不是逃跑
To finish the job.
而是完成計劃
Are you crazy, Dom? We can't.
多姆  你瘋了嗎  我們辦不到
It's a suicide mission.
這無疑是在自殺
That's your man over there on the table.
你兄弟還躺在那堳肭岩撈H
The plan is busted!
計劃破產了
This is bullshit, man. Reyes knows we're coming!
都是胡扯  雷耶斯知道我們要去
He's right.
他說的對
They tripled the detail at the police station.
他們增派了三倍的人手在警察局
it's going to be a wall of gunfire.
這將是一場血戰
Reyes doesn't get away with this.
不能輕易饒了雷耶斯
It's a trap, man.
這是個陷阱  夥計
You know that.
你早知道
Dom, listen to them.
多姆  聽他們的吧
Run, before it's too late. Leave Rio.
趁還有機會  逃吧  離開堿
You can be free.
你就自由了
Running ain't freedom.
逃跑不會自由
You should know that.
你應該明白的
You know you're all free to make your own choices.
你們自己有權決定去留
I'm in.
我入伙
I'll ride with you, Toretto.
特若圖  我和你一起去
At least until we kill that son of a bitch.
最起碼殺了那個狗娘養的
So what's the plan, Dom?
多姆  那計劃是什麼
We can't just go sneaking around anymore.
想藏也藏不住了
We don't sneak.
我們不藏
The only thing he cares about is his money.
他唯一在意的就是他的錢
We pull that,
我們控制了錢
we pull him.
也就控制了他
See?
看到了嗎
I called in every cop on our payroll.
全部警員出動
We're covered.
萬無一失
We've got every entrance covered with weapons teams.
每個入口都有人守衛
God Himself couldn't get at your money if He wanted to.
即使上帝也不可能拿走您的錢
God isn't my worry.
我可不擔心上帝
You ready?
準備好了嗎
I'm ready.
準備好了
What's happening?
發生什麼事了
They're taking the vault!
他們來打劫了
- What? - The vault!
-什麼  -金庫
Follow me! Quickly!
跟我來  快點
Let me through!
讓我過去
Don't move!
不許動
Stay down.
趴下
Call it out, Mia!
米亞  路況
You've got a straight shot for two blocks.
直走  兩個街區
- Go right.- Got it.
-右轉  -好
Well, the plan is working.
不出意料
You guys have every corrupt cop in Rio on your tail.
堿讞狾釭瘧筐拿ㄕb追你們
You have to move fast.
你們得跑快一點
What's the best route?
最佳落點在哪
Okay, keep going straight another half-mile onto Rua Fonseca,
向前行駛半英里到的盧福
and then go left.
然後左轉
That ain't going to work.
行不通
Spikes ahead, Dom. We got spikes!
多姆  前面有釘子  有釘子
We're going right!
往右開
No, it's too tight, we're not going to fit.
不行  太擠了  過不去
We've got no choice. Now!
沒選擇了  立刻
Shit!
狗屎
Holy shit!
真要命
Guys, I am hearing all this chatter.
夥計們  我都聽到動靜了
Did you just take out a bank?
你們把銀行拖出來了啊
Two inbound!
來了兩輛
All right, there's an alley coming up on your left.
好的  你們左側有個巷子
Yeah, I got it.
好的  知道了
You little bastard!
王八蛋
All right, good job, Dom. Right-hander, right here, right-hander.
不錯  多姆  這堨k轉
Guys, there's a big group coming at you from the south.
南邊追過去一大隊人馬
You have to do something now!
你們想想辦法
Hey, go wide.
分開兩側
You're all clear on the left.
左側障礙清除
Good afternoon, officer!
下午好  警官
License and registration, please!
請您出示駕照
Yes! This is big-boy stuff!
帥呆了
We're clear on the right.
右側障礙清除
Oh, man.
厲害
Thanks, guys.
謝謝夥計們
Any time.
隨叫隨到
I'll see you on the other side.
一會兒見
You guys just carved out a 10-second window.
你們只有十秒鐘
Make it count!
抓緊時間
Zizi, stay on them.
齊齊  跟緊他們
They can't outrun us on the bridge.
在橋上他們甩不掉我們的
Shit.
該死
They have no way out.
無路可逃吧
No!
不
There's too many of them.
他們人太多了
Hey, there's too many of them. We're not going to make it.
我們沒辦法甩掉的
You're right, we aren't.
是的  我們甩不掉
You are.
甩掉你可以
What are you talking about?
什麼意思
Just let the vault go. Get out of there.
甩掉金庫  離開那
You're a father now, Brian.
布萊恩  你是有孩子的人了
No, I'm not leaving you. Now you stick with the plan!
我不會丟下你的  你按計劃來
It was always the plan.
計劃本來就如此
Take care of Mia.
照顧好米亞
Dom, you listen to me now. Okay?
多姆  你現在聽我說
You cut loose right now.
立刻切斷繩索
Hey, what is he doing?
他要幹什麼
We've got him!
我們要抓到他了
Close down the bridge!
封閉大橋
Do something, asshole!
想想辦法  混蛋
Kill him, dammit!
殺掉他  媽的
Kill him now!
幹掉他  快點
I thought I told you to go on.
不是讓你別回頭嗎
Yeah, I had to make a call.
沒錯  但我的幹完這筆
Help me.
救我
That's for my team, you son of a bitch.
狗雜種  這槍是為了我兄弟們
It's a hell of a mess.
簡直一團糟啊
Yeah, it is.
是的
You know I can't let you two go.
我不可能放你們走
I ain't made that way.
這與我的職責不符
The way I see it, you've earned yourselves 24 hours.
我給你二十四小時的時間
The money stays, though.
但是錢要留下
If I were you, I'd use the time.
如果我是你  我會好好利用這個時間
Make peace with whatever demons you got left.
把該處理的事情都處理好
Because come tomorrow,
到了明天
I will find you.
我就去抓你們
Toretto!
特若圖
I'll see you soon.
後會有期
No, you won't.
不  後會無期
Thanks, guys.
謝啦  夥計們
I'll see you on the other side.
一會見
You guys just carved out a 10 second window.
你們只有十秒鐘
Make it count!
抓緊時間
Come on, baby.
拜託  寶貝
Don't be mean.
別為難我
Come on.
拜託
For Rosa and Nico. See you soon,
給羅莎和尼克  再見  多姆叔叔
You sure about this?
你確定要這麼做嗎
You know I am.
你知道的  當然
You don't need to do this.
你不必如此的
Just leave me alone.
別煩我了
Bro, I'm not trying to be negative, but casinos
夥計  我不是反對你
are the kinds of places
只是賭場
designed to take money from guys like you and me.
就是專門坑我們這種人的地方
When I win here I'm buying
等我贏了
you a lifetime supply of antidepressants.
給你夠吃一輩子的抗抑鬱藥
You don't put ten million on red!
不要把一千萬都押紅色
Enough already.
夠了
You put it on black.
押黑色
No more bets.
停止下注
Right this way, my dear.
這邊  甜心
You stay right here, I'll be right back.
待在這  我馬上回來
So, this is your dream, huh?
這就是你的夢想了啊
It's enough for me, man.
這對我足夠了
I take it that's your dream.
看來你也實現夢想了
Absolutely. What up, boy? What's going on?
當然  怎麼樣...
- You good? - Yes, yes.
-你不錯啊  -是的
You know what's crazy?
你知道多瘋狂嗎
There's only four of those cars in the whole world.
這車全球只有四輛
Yeah, I got the only one in the Western Hemisphere.
我擁有西半球唯一的一輛
I made a sheikh in Abu Dhabi an offer he could not refuse.
我給了阿布扎比酋長一個無法拒絕的高價
Huh. That's a nice lady you got there, too.
那個姑娘也不錯
Absolutely. What's happening?
那是當然
We got to go, man. Let's do this.
夥計  我們要出發了  走吧
Okay, I'll drive.
好的  我要開車
In that? Come on, man, no way.
這個嗎  拜託 夥計 別...沒門
No, no. Not in this.
不  不是這個
In that.
那個
Are you serious right now?
你不是在開玩笑吧
Man, this is crazy!
夥計  這太瘋狂了
Yes, I guess that means
是的  這意味著
there are two in the Western Hemisphere, huh?
在西半球有兩輛這個車了
What's your smart ass got to say now?
現在你個大忽悠要說點什麼
You know what? We can always shine together, baby.
我們可以一直結伴出去拉風了
Get dressed, man, we got things to do!
換衣服  夥計  我們要出發了
So, where to now?
現在去哪
I don't know.
我也不知道
Never been to Madrid.
從沒去過馬德里
I thought you wanted to go to Tokyo.
我以為你會去東京
We'll get there.
我們會去的...
Eventually.
最後去...
Nice surprise.
沒想到你會來
Crazy, right?
瘋狂
This is the happiest I've ever seen my sister.
這是我見過的老妹最幸福的時候
It's because we're free.
因為自由
You know, I want another shot.
我想再比一次
Yeah?
是嗎
Yeah.
是的
No wagers, nobody else.
沒有賭注  沒有別人
Just you and me, once and for all.
就你和我  只此一次
You sure you can handle the disappointment?
你確定能承受失敗的打擊嗎
Are you?
你呢
All right, O'Conner.
好吧  歐康納
Diplomatic security service headquarters - Washington, d.C.
外交保安局總部  華盛頓
You need to look at that.
你看下這個
Berlin. 3:00 a.m. This morning.
柏林  今晨三點
A team of drivers hijacked a military convoy.
一隊車手搶劫了一輛軍用運輸車
- Toretto? - Nope.
-特若圖嗎  -不是
I ain't interested.
不感興趣
Yes, you are. Keep looking.
不  你會感興趣  繼續看
Do you believe in ghosts?
相信活見鬼了嗎